Guide to the Hotels Statler Company records, 1885-1988.
Hotels Statler Company records, 1885-1988
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hotels Statler Company records, 1885-1988.
4303
Carl G., Thurston
5.6 cubic ft.
Manuals, instructions, surveys, historical records, publications, newsletters, and memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Statler standard instruction manuals for accounting and finance, housekeeping, employee training and job descriptions; folders on the history of the hotels, instructions and procedures, wage surveys; sales and convention information; executive training materials; publications, newsletters, and memorabilia. Also includes newsletters and other items relating to the Statler Alumni Club.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Statler standard instruction manuals for accounting and finance, housekeeping, employee training and job descriptions; folders on the history of the hotels, instructions and procedures, wage surveys; sales and convention information; executive training materials; publications, newsletters, and memorabilia. Also includes newsletters and other items relating to the Statler Alumni Club.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Thurston, Carl G.,; Hotels Statler Company.; Statler Alumni Club.
Subjects:
Hotel management.; Hotels--Employees.; Hotels--Finance.; Hotel housekeeping.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Accounting Manual, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Accounting Manual, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
- Management Development Conferences, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Management Development in the Hotel Industry, 1943-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Hotel Pennsylvania - Telephone Operating Practice, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Standard Instructions - Accounting; Other Departments A25000, copy for Mr. Bone, 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Standard Instructions - Auditing; Miscellaneous A2000, copy for Mr. Bone, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Standard Instructions - Payroll A6000, copy for Mr. Bone, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Classification of Accounts, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Standard Instructions - Credit, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Tax Instruction Manual, 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
- Sales Manual - Hotel Statler, Buffalo, 1885; 1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Convention Facts - Hotel Statler, Buffalo (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Constructive Talks to Pivot Men, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
- Bulletins, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
- Hartford, Connecticut, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 27-29)
- Report on System and Procedures, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Employee Training, AHA Convention, Montreal, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Wage Analysis - New York State Hotel Association, 1952-1960 (Box 1, Folder 32-34)
- Annual Report, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Statler Personnel Managers' Conference, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- C.G. Thurston - Housekeeping, 1932-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Training - H.S. Co. - Thurston, 1949-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- C.G. Thurston - Duties and Responsibilities, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General Survey of Hotels Statler, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- History of Hotels Statler, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Housekeeping, 1948-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Personnel Manager Papers (Miscellaneous), 1939-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Procedures, 1938-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Service Department - Standard Instructions, 1931-1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Strike, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Standard Instructions, 1931-1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Turnover Studies, 1951-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Wage Survey, 1949; 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous File #1, 1937-1954; 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous File #2, 1926-1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- School of Hotel Administration, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- Hotel Ezra Cornell (HEC) (Box 2, Folder 19-22)
- HEC 60, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
- Thomas E. Silk Board Room, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
- Standard Recipes (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Standard Bar Recipes (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
- Safety Council Manual, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Annual Reports, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Hotel Monthly - Los Angeles Statler and Hartford Statler, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Statler Articles (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Statler - Washington D.C. (reprint), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Hotel Management - Los Angeles Statler, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- The Hotel World - Review: 75 Years of Hotel History, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Statler Club Alumni News, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Statler Club Alumni News, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Housekeeping Manual (2 copies), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
- Carl Thurston correspondence and memos concerning Hotels Statler Company, 1947-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Statler Memorabilia (Box 3)
  Coffee can, ash tray, dinner plate, HEC photograph album, marble paperweight inscribed "Hotel Statler, Buffalo 1923-1984," brick "From the first permanent Statler Hotel" - Hotel Statler, Buffalo, N.Y.
- Statler Guides, November 1937-January 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Statler Bulletins for Department Meetings, June 1925-Decenber 1927 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Statler Bulletins for Department Meetings, January 1928-April 1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Talks to Statler Salesmen, January 1929-December 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Statler Salesmanship, June 1923, 1931, June 1932 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Talks to Department Heads, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Talks to Room Clerks; Talks to Waiters and Waitresses; Instructions to Room Service Waiters, Bellmen, Maids, 1929-1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Be a Clever Cover Girl: A Guide for Statler Waitresses" (2 copies), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Inside Statler" (2 copies), 1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Statler Service Codes"- booklets from three different years, no dates (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "The Successful Waitress" - General Foods Corp., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Statler Publicity", 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Hotel Statler Booklets from Buffalo, St. Louis, Detroit, Cleveland, no dates (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Hotel Credit Department Legal Guide and Practical Procedures"- Hotel Association of New York City, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Hotel Statler Personnel Policies, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "The Efficiency Magazine", October 1945 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Hotel" the magazine of the hotel workers of New York, November 1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "The New York Hotel Story" - Industrial Bulletin, February 1951 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "The Alarm Clock" - Monthly Bulletin issued by the staff of Horwath and Horwath, September 1928 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Service Reports, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- General Rules for Employees - Hotel Pennsylvania, no dates (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Hotel Management Clipping Bureau of Good Ideas, September 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Statler and Hilton Memo Books for Daily Follow-Up, September 1928 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "When Good Fellows Get Together" - Wines and Liquors Manual, September 1933 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Culinary Glossaries - Spanish, Austro-German, French, Italian - Wine and Food Society, no dates (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Mine Hosts Handbook", 1934 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Hotel McLure - Wheeling, West Virginia, no date (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Architecture" - The Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, November 1931 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Waldorf-Astoria Magazine, March 1935, February 1936 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Postcards from various Statler Hotels, Statler Corkscrew, Decals, no dates (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "The Story of the Los Angeles Statler", 1953 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Booklet and Menu from Opening of the Statler Center in Los Angeles, October 1952 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Pastel of E.M. Statler (Box 5)
- Photograph of the Centennial Freshman Class at Cornell University Centennial Banquet (Box 5)
- Photograph of Dinner given by James McCabe, 1949 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Hotel Statler - Boston (Box 5)
- Photograph of the Hotel Statler Employees' Choral Club - Buffalo, 1953 (Box 5)
- Photograph of 20 Year Employees - Hotel Statler, Boston, 1947 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Dinner Given by James McCabe, 1946 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Dinner Given by James McCabe, 1947 (Box 5)
- Photograph of 11th Annual Christmas Party, 1933 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Statler Bowling Tournament, 1949 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Statler Bowling Tournament, 1950 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Hotels Statler Co., Inc. Founders Day Dinner, 1952 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Hotels Statler Co., Inc. Founders Day, 1951 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Hotel Statler Executive Office Christmas Party, 1950 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Farewell Dinner Party to Don Mumford, 1948 (Box 5)
- Photograph of 4th Annual Founders Day Dinner, 1947 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Mr. McCabe's Dinner, 1942 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Mr. McCabe's Dinner, 1941 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Mr. McKowne's Dinner, 1937 (Box 5)
- Photograph of Dinner Given by James McCabe, 1950 (Box 5)
- Saturday Evening Post - Hotels Statler, 1918 (Box 5)
- Newspaper "Public Ledger - Philadelphia" - article about opening of Hotel Pennsylvania, 1919 (Box 5)
- "Class" Quotes and Policies by E.M. Statler, ca. 1927 (Box 5)
- Addition to Collection - not donated by Carl Thurston
  - Articles about Waiters in Bound Volume, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Stationery and Articles in Bound Volume, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook of Clippings - Courtesy Advertising, 1908 (Box 6)
  - Reproductions of Articles concerning the Statler Enterprises, 1898-1928 (Box 6)
  - Interim Report on Automation for Hotels by Profesoor C.I. Sayles, January 1961 (Box 6)
  - "The Union Organization of the Miami Beach Hotels - By John Hanly, 1962 (Box 6)
  - "The Miami Beach Hotel Labor-Management Dispute March-August 1955" - by John Harney (Box 6)
  - Hotel and Restaurant History - Brochures, Publications, 1920s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
  - Receipts from various hotels, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Banquet and Entertainment Price Schedules and Requirements, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - "Front of the House" - Lewis Hotel-Motel Schools - Five LP Phonograph records, no dates (Box 6)
  - Speech on International Travel, no date (Box 6)
  - "An American Adventure" the story of Ellsworth Statler, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Various Hotels, no dates (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Postcards of London, no dates (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Public Relations Achievement Award Competition - Waldorf-Astoria Entry, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11-15)
  - Statler Center Los Angeles Floor Plans, 1951 (Box 6)
  - Hotel Statler Hartford - Floor Plans, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook containing articles about various hotels, 1895-1930s (Box 7)
  - Photo of President Harding and Letter to Oscar of the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, 1923-09 (Box 7)
  - Lewis Hotel Training Schools - Practice Work Sheets and Exams, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Lewis Hotel Training Schools - Poster and Memos, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Button from hotel uniform (Box 4, Folder 14)